Finding Aid for Vandenberg family papers, 1923-1965
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Vandenberg Family papers 1923-1965
Vandenberg family
1 linear foot.
86162 Aa 2
Letters of Senator Arthur H. Vandenberg with family members John and Barbara Bailey; also papers of Arthur H. Vandenberg, Jr., aide to President Dwight Eisenhower, largely concerning Republican politics, 1948-1952, and election of 1952.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers were received from Arthur Vandenberg, Jr. and Elizabeth Vandenberg Sands. 5425
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Vandenberg family of Grand Rapids Michigan and Washington D.C., including Senator Arthur H. Vandenberg., his wife Hazel Harper (Whitaker) Vandenberg and their children Arthur Jr., Barbara and Elizabeth..
The Vandenberg Family papers, 1923-1965, and Washington, D.C.; include letters of Arthur H. Vandenberg with family members John and Barbara Bailey; also papers of Arthur H. Vandenberg, Jr., aide to President D. Eisenhower, largely concerning republican politics, 1948-1952, and the election of 1952. Correspondents include: Thomas Dewey, Dvight Eisenhower, and Nelson Rockefeller.
Subjects:
Grand Rapids (Mich.); Presidents--United States--Election--1952.; Women--Michigan--Grand Rapids.; Republican Party (Mich.); United States--Politics and government--1953-1961.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1953.; Washington (D.C.)
Contributors:
Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Vandenberg, Arthur Hendrick, 1907-1968.
- Correspondence, 1923-1958
  - Correspondence, 1923-1946, of AHV with Barbara V. Bailey (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1951, of AHV with John W. Bailey (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1958, of AHV, jr.. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1925-1926, of AHV, jr. written to family from Dartmouth (Box 1)
  - Family correspondence, 1949-1965, of AHV Jr. (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous family correspondence (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1956, of AHV, Jr. with Dwight D. Eisenhower (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Speeches and newspaper clippings (Box 1)
  - Eisenhower memorabilia (Box 1)
  - Lecture materials, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - AHV, Sr. estate materials (Box 1)
  - Far East and Latin American notes (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 1)
  - "The Private Papers of Senator Vandenberg" materials (Box 1)
  - Newspaper reviews of "The Private Papers of Senator Vandenberg", 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Military service file,1942-1946 (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks
  - [Vol. 1] 1952 concerning political campaign (Box 1)
  - [Vol. 2] 1939-1949 (Box 1)